<resources>
    <string name="app_name">SmartFarming</string>
    <string name="title_activity_crop_practices">CropPracticesActivity</string>
    <string name="paddy_brown_leaf_spot">Symptoms: \n1. Infected seedlings have small, circular, yellow brown or brown lesions that may girdle the coleoptile and distort primary and secondary leaves. \n2. Starting at tillering stage, lesions can be observed on the leaves. They are initially small, circular, and dark brown to purple-brown. 3. Fully developed lesions are circular to oval with a light brown to gray center, surrounded by a reddish brown margin caused by the toxin produced by the fungi. \n\nManagement: \n1. Seed treatment with Captan or Thiram at 2.0g/kg of seed \n2. Spraying tricyclazole followed by spraying of mancozeb + tricyclazole at tillering and late booting stages gave good control of the disease. 3. use Propineb 70% WP - 400 g/acre \n4. Seed treatment with Pseudomonas fluorescens @10g/kg of seed followed by seedling dip @ of 2.5 kg/ha dissolved in 100 litres and dipping for 30 minutes.</string>
    <string name="paddy_bacterial_leaf_blight">Symptoms: \n• Lesions are elliptical and tan in color, developing distinct dark areas as they mature that are associated with fungal sporulation.Lesions typically first appear on lower leaves, spreading to upper leaves and the ear sheaths as the crop matures. \n• Under severe infection, lesions may coalesce, blighting the entire leaf. \n\nManagement: \n1. Soak the seeds with a solution of plantomycin 10gms or streptocyclin 1.5gms and copper oxychloride 25gms in 10 litres of water. \n2. Spray the affected crop with the same chemicals at 500 litres /ha at 7–10 days intervals 2–3 times on need basis. \n3. Use fresh cow dung slurry at 2kg/10 litres of water, strain it in fine cloth and spray at an interval of 7–10 days 3–4 times at 250 liter of water per acre \n4. Pseudomonas fluorescens and Bacillus strain 3 FZB42 are found effective against this infestation</string>
    <string name="paddy_harvesting">Taking the average duration of the crop as an indication, drain the water from the field 7 to 10 days before the expected harvest date as draining hastens maturity and improves harvesting conditions. \n\nWhen 80% of the panicles turn straw colour, the crop is ready for harvest. Even at this stage, the leaves of some of the varieties may remain green. \n\nConfirm maturity by selecting the most mature tiller and dehusk a few grains. If the rice is clear and firm, it is in hard dough stage. \n\nWhen most of the grains at the base of the panicle in the selected tiller are in a hard dough stage, the crop is ready for harvest. At this stage harvest the crop, thresh and winnow the grains. \n\nDry the grains to 12% moisture level for storage. Grain yield in rice is estimated only at 14% moisture for any comparison. \nMaturity may be hastened by 3–4 days by spraying 20% NaCl a week before harvest to escape monsoon rains.</string>

    <string name="large_text">…</string>

    <string name="maize_introduction">Globally, Maize is known as queen of cereals because it has hte highest genetic yield potential among the cereals. It is cultivated on nearly 150 m ha in about 160 countries having wider diversity of soil, climate, biodiversity and management practices that contributes 36% (782 m t) in the global grain production.
        \n\nIn India, Maize is the 3rd most important food crops after rice and wheat. It is cultivated under a wide range of agro-ecological situations. In addition to staple food for human being and quality feed for animals.
        \n\nMaize serves as a basic raw material as ana ingredient to thousands of industrial products that includes starch, oil, protein, alcoholic beverages, food sweeteners, pharmaceutical, cosmetic, film, textile, gum, package and paper industries etc.</string>
    <string name="maize_climate">Maize can be grown in temperature high lands, tropical as well as sub-tropical regions. \nA moderate temperature, adequate moisture is basic need of Maize crop. \nHowever, the crop is susceptive to water logging condition, which needs to be avoided.</string>
    <string name="maize_soil">Maize requires a well-drained sandy loam soil with organic matter. \nit thrives well in soil pH between 5.5 to 8.0.</string>
    <string name="maize_sowing">Method of sowing : \n \nMaize seed should be sown with dibbling or drilling method. It is depending on purpose of sowing, type of Maize, varieties and farm condition. \nSeed should be sown at depth of 3–4 cm. For sweet corn cultivation keep depth of sowing to 2.5 cm.</string>
    <string name="maize_seed">\n\nSeed rate : \nThe seed rate varies depending on purpose, seed size, plant type, season, sowing methods etc.</string>
    <string name="maize_land_preparation">A well prepared flat–beds which has given 4–5 deep ploughing provided an ideal condition for sowing of crop. \nFYM or compost : 5 tonn / acre. \n \nNOTE : \nDO not leave the organic manure exposed to sunlight as nutrients will be lost.</string>
    <string name="maize_fertilizers">Apply fertilizers based on soil test results N:P:K = 40:30:20 kg/acre. \n\nUrea should be applied in 3 splits, mainly at sowing, knee–high and tasselling stages. Entire dose of P &amp; K20 with 40 KG urea should be applied at the time of sowing. \n\nApply Criyagen DNP 2 bags as basal dose/acre. Apply Criyagen Zinc sulphate : 10kg/acre. \n\nFoliar Spray : Biomaxx @ 3ml/liter + All 19 @ 5gm/liter at tassel initiation and at grain filling stages  improves grain filling, grain yield and drought tolerance. \n\nApply : Urea 80–120 kg/acre, DAP / SSP 30–60 or 100–150 kg/acre, MOP 18 kg/acre.</string>
    <string name="maize_irrigation">For Kharif Maize, irrigation at early knee–high, tasselling and 50% silking stages are to be given. \n\nFor rabi Maize, first irrigation is to be applied 3–4 week after seedling emergence, subsequently at 4–5 weeks till March and thereafter at 1–2 weeks interval.\n</string>
    <string name="maize_downy_mildew">Symptoms: \nChlorotic streaks appear on the leaf and white fungus growth is seen on both the surfaces of leaf. \nAffected plants become stunted and exhibit bushy appearance due to shortening of internodes. \nSometimes leafy growths in the tassel and proliferation of axillary buds on the stalk of the tassel are noticed. \n\nManagement : \n- Soil application of P.fluorescens (or) T.viride @ 2.5 kg/ha + 50 kg of well decomposed FYM (mix 10 days before application) or sand at 30 days after sowing. \n- Spray Metalaxyl @ 1000g (or) Mancozeb 2g/lit at 20 days after sowing.\n</string>
    <string name="maize_charcoal_rot">Symptoms: \n- The pathogen affects the plant mostly after flowering and the disease is named as Post Flowering Stalk Rot (PFSR). \n- The stalk of the infected plants can be recognized by greyish streak. \n- The pith becomes shredded and greyish black minute sclerota develop on the vascular bundles. \n\nManagement : \n- Follow crop rotation. \n- Avoidance of water stress at flowering time reduced disease incidence. \n- Avoid nutrient stress. \n- Apply potash @ 80 kg/ha in endemic areas. \n- Soil application of Psedomonas. fluorescens (or) Trichoderma. virid @ 2.5 kg/ha + 50 kg of well decomposed FYM (mix 10 days before application) or sand at 30 days after sowing.\n</string>
    <string name="maize_harvesting">Maize is ready for harvesting even when the stacks and leaves are somewhat green but the husk cover has dried and turned brown. Shell Maize when the moisture content ranges between 15–20%. \n\nConventional harvester combines can be used for threshing Maize with husk to save labour involved in dehusking. \n\nThe Maize ears should be dried for 3–4 days after harvesting to improve grain recoveries and reduce breakage losses during shelling.</string>
    <string name="maize_yield">- Local Varieties : 15 to 20 quintals (grain) per hectare. \n\n- High Yielding Varieties : 40 to 50 quintals (grain) per hectare.</string>

    <string name="pearl_millet_introduction">Bajra is popularly known as "pearl millet" and belongs to the family of Gramineae. This grain is basically originated from India or Africa. \n\nBajra is a coarse grain crop and considered to be the poor man\'s staple nourishment and suitable to cultivate in dry-lands. Major Bajra production states in India are Rajasthan, Maharashtra, Haryana, Uttar Pradesh, and Gujarat. \n\nBajra can also be used as valuable animal fodder. It is one of the major crops of China, India, South-Eastern Asia, Sudan, Pakistan, Arabia, Russia &amp; Nigeria.</string>
    <string name="pearl_millet_climate">Bajra grows well in dry and warm climatic conditions and it\'s drought-tolerant crop which requires low annual rainfall ranging between 40 cm to 60 cm. \n\nThe ideal temperature for Bajra cultivation is between 20°C to 30°C. Moist weather is advantageous during its vegetative growth. \n\nIn North India, Bajra is grown as Kharif crop and in some southern parts is grown as summer crop providing Irrigation</string>
    <string name="pearl_millet_soil">Bajra can be grown in a wide range of soils. However, It thrives best in black cotton soils, sandy loam soils having good drainage. \n\nThis crop does not prefer acidic and waterlogging soils. Avoid saturated soils for its cultivation. It grows successfully well in soils with low pH (or) high salinity. Bajra can be easily grown in regions where other cereal crops like wheat or maize would not survive.</string>
    <string name="pearl_millet_sowing_seed">Sowing of kharif pearl millet should be done with the onset of monsoon i.e. first fortnight of July in north and central parts of the country. \n\nFirst fortnight of October is appropriate time for rabi season in Tamil Nadu. Gap filling should be done by transplanting seedlings after 2–3 weeks of sowing if scanty population exists. \n\nIn Marathwada area of Maharashtra, dry sowing prior to first monsoon rains is recommended. Summer pearl millet should be sown from 4th to 5th Standard Meteorological Week (SMW) i.e. last week of January to 1st week of February to obtain higher production of summer pearl millet in zone B. \n\nSeed Rate : \n1.5 to 1.7 kg/acre for dibbling method. 2 to 2.5 kg/acre for the drilling method. Row spacing of 40 cm to 45 cm should be maintained and within rows, 10 cm - 15 cm should be kept.</string>
    <string name="pearl_millet_land_preparation">2 to 3 harrowing followed by a plowing is required to make the soil in the field to the fine tilth. Any weeds should be destroyed during the field preparation to accommodate proper sowing and distribution of seed at an appropriate depth.</string>
    <string name="pearl_millet_downwy_mildew">Symptoms : \nThe characteristic symptoms of the disease are pale, chlorotic, broad streaks extending from base to tip of leaves. \nAt the advancement of disease, the leaf streaks turn brown and the leaves become shredded longitudinally. In severe infection, the downy fungal growth can be seen on the upper as well as lower surface of the leaves. \n\nThe rapid growth of fungal pathogen is favoured by rainy and humid environment. The infected plants fail to form ear but if formed, they are malformed to green leafy structures. \n\nThe complete ear can be transformed into leafy structures. \nThe fungal pathogen transformed all floral parts such as glumes, palea, stamens and pistils into green linear leafy structures of variable lengths. \n\nAs the disease advances, the malformed floral structures of ears become brown and dry. \n\nManagement : \nSpray Chlorothalonil 75% WP {Chlorothalonil 75% WP30ml/pump. Or use Kresoxim Methyl 44.3% SC { Ergon (TATA)} ☐ 150 ml/acre.\n</string>
    <string name="pearl_millet_rust">Symptoms : \nOn pearl millet: small reddish–brown to reddish orange, round to elliptical uredinia develop mainly on foliage. \nAs severity of infection increases, leaf tissue will wilt and become necrotic from the leaf apex to base. \nIn infection sites developing late in the season, uredinia are replaced by telia which are black, elliptical, and sub epidermal. \n\nManagement : \nSpray Hexaconazole 5% EC { Contaf (TATA)}, 400ml/acre or use Mancozeb 75% WP { Dithane M–45 (Dow)}, 400–600gm/acre \n</string>
    <string name="pearl_millet_harvesting">The crop is ready for harvesting when the grain become hardy &amp; contain moisture. Two methods can be followed in harvesting. \n\nBajra crop: Cutting earhead or cutting of entire plants by sticks. stalk the cut plants for 4 to 5 days in the sun for drying grains. Grains can be separated by beating the earheads</string>
    <string name="pearl_millet_yield">Rainfed crop yields about 6 to 8 quintals/acre and irrigated crop yields about 12 to 17 quintals/ acre. \n\nThe yield also depends on the soil type, variety, season, and cultivation practices.</string>


    <string name="tomato_intro">Tomato, (Solanum lycopersicum), flowering plant of the nightshade family (Solanaceae), cultivated extensively for its edible fruits. \nLabelled as a vegetable for nutritional purposes, tomatoes are a good source of vitamin C and the phytochemical lycopene. \n\nThe fruits are commonly eaten raw in salads, served as a cooked vegetable, used as an ingredient of various prepared dishes, and pickled. \n\nAdditionally, a large percentage of the worlds tomato crop is used for processing; products include canned tomatoes, tomato juice, ketchup, puree, paste, and "sun-dried" tomatoes or dehydrated pulp.</string>
    <string name="tomato_climate">Tomato is a warm season crop. The best fruit colour and quality is obtained at a temperature range of 21–24°C. \nTemperatures above 32°C adversely affects the fruit set and development. \n\nThe plants cannot withstand frost and high humidity. It requires a low to medium rainfall. Bright sunshine at the time of fruit set helps to develop dark red coloured fruits. \n\nTemperature below 10 degree C adversely affects plant tissues thereby slowing down physiological activities.</string>
    <string name="tomato_soil">Tomato can be grown on a wide range of soils from sandy to heavy clay. However, well–drained, sandy or red loam soils rich in organic matter with a pH range of 6.0–7.0 are considered as ideal.</string>
    <string name="tomato_sowing_and_seed">Time of sowing : \nSeeds are sown in June July for autumn winter crop and for spring summer crop seeds are sown in November. In the hills seed is sown in March April. \n\nNursery bed preparation \nApply FYM 10 kg, Neem cake 1 kg, VAM 50 g, enriched Super-phosphate 100 g and Furadon 10 g per square meter before sowing. \n\nProtected Nursery \n• Prepare the nursery area of 3 cents with slanting slope of 2% for the seedling production to cover 1 ha. \n\n• Cover the nursery area with 50 % shade net and cover the sides using 40/50 mesh insect proof nylon net. \n\n• Form raised beds of 1 m width and convenient length and place HDPV pipes at 2m interval for further protection with polythene sheets during rainy months. \n\n• Mix sterilized coco peat @ 300 kg with 5 kg neem cake along with Azospirillum and Phosphobacteria each @ 1 kg. Approximately 1.2 kg of cocopeat is required for filling one portray. 238 portrays (98 cells) are required for the production of 23,334 seedlings, which are required for one hectare.</string>
    <string name="tomato_land_preparation_and_manuring">Plough the land to fine tilth. Thoroughly prepare the field with the addition of FYM @ 25 t/ha and form ridges and furrows at a spacing of 60 cm. \n\nApply 2 kg/ha of Azospirillum and 2 kg/ha of Phosphobacteria by mixing with 50 kg of FYM. \n\nIrrigate the furrows and transplant 25 days old seedlings on the sides of ridges. Life irrigation to be given on 3rd day of planting.</string>
    <string name="tomato_fertilizers">The fertilizer dose depends upon the fertility of soil and amount of organic manure applied to the crop. For a good yield, 15–20 tonnes of well–decomposed FYM is incorporated into the soil. \n\nGenerally, application of 120 kg N, 80 kg P205 and 50 kg K20 per hectare is recommended for getting optimum yield. Half dose of N and full dose of P and K is given at the time of planting. \n\nThe balance half of N is given as top dressing 30 days after transplanting. \n\nFor hybrid varieties, the recommended dose per hectare is 180 kg N, 100 kg P2 05 and 60 kg K2 O. 60 kg N and half of P &amp; K are given at the time of transplanting. \n\nRemaining quantities of P &amp; K and 60 kg N is top dressed 30 after transplanting. A third dose of 60 kg N is applied 50 days after transplanting. \n\nSpray 1.25 ppm (625 ml in 500 litres of water) Triacontanol/ BIOMAXX/HORTICULTURE SPECIAL 400–500ML/ACRE at 15 days after transplanting and at full bloom stage to increase the yield. \n• Foliar spray of ZnSO4 @ 0.5 per cent thrice at 1</string>
    <string name="tomato_damping_off">Symptoms : \n• Damping off of tomato occurs in two stages, i.e. the pre-emergence and the post-emergence phase. \n• In the pre-emergence the phase the seedlings are killed just before they reach the soil surface. \n• The young radical and the plumule are killed and there is complete rotting of the seedlings. \n• The post-emergence phase is characterized by the infection of the young, juvenile tissues of the collar at the ground level. \n• The infected tissues become soft and water soaked. The seedlings topple over or collapse. \n\nManagement : \n• Used raised seed bed \n• Provide light, but frequent irrigation for better drainage. \n• Drench with Copper oxychloride 0.2% or Bordeaux mixture 1%. \n• Seed treatment with fungal culture Trichoderma viride (4 g/kg of seed) or Thiram (3 g/kg of seed) is the only preventive measure to control the pre-emergence damping off. \n• Spray 0.2% Metalaxyl when there is cloudy weather.</string>
    <string name="tomato_early_blight">Symptoms : \n• This is a common disease of tomato occurring on the foliage at any stage of the growth. \n• The fungus attacks the foliage causing characteristic leaf spots and blight. Early blight is first observed on the plants as small, black lesions mostly on the older foliage. \n• Spots enlarge, and by the time they are one-fourth inch in diameter or larger, concentric rings in a bull\'s eye pattern can be seen in the center of the diseased area. \n• Tissue surrounding the spots may turn yellow. If high temperature and humidity occur at this time, much of the foliage is killed. \n• Lesions on the stems are similar to those on leaves, sometimes girdling the plant if they occur near the soil line. \n• Transplants showing infection by the late blight fungus often die when set in the field. The fungus also infects the fruit, generally through the calyx or stem attachment. \n• Lesions attain considerable size, usually involving nearly the entire fruit; concentric rings are also present on the fru</string>
    <string name="tomato_bacterial_leaf_spot">Symptom : \n• Moist weather and splattering rains are conducive to disease development. Most outbreaks of the disease can be traced back to heavy rainstorms that occur in the area. \n• Infected leaves show small, brown, water soaked, circular spots surrounded with yellowish halo. \n• On older plants the leaflet infection is mostly on older leaves and may cause serious defoliation. \n• The most striking symptoms are on the green fruit. Small, water-soaked spots first appear which later become raised and enlarge until they are one-eighth to one-fourth inch in diameter. \n\nManagement : \n• Disease-free seed and seedlings should always be used and the crop should be rotated with non-host crops so as to avoid last years crop residue. \n• Seed treatment with mercuric chloride (1:1000) is also recommended for control of disease. \n• Spraying with a combination of copper and organic fungicides in a regular preventative spray program at 5 to 10 day intervals or Spraying with Agrimycin-100 (100 ppm) thrice at 10 days intervals effectively controls the disease.</string>
    <string name="tomato_harvesting">Depending on the variety, fruits become ready for first picking in about 60–70 days after transplanting. The stage of harvesting depends upon the purpose to which the fruits are to be used. The different stages of harvesting are as follows- \n\n• Dark green colour - Dark green colour is changed and a reddish pink shade is observed on fruit. Fruits to be shipped are harvested at this stage. Such fruits are then sprayed with ethylene 48 hours prior to shipping. Immature green tomatoes will ripen poorly and be of low quality. \n\nA simple way to determine maturity is to slice the tomato with a sharp knife. If seeds are cut, the fruit is too immature for harvest and will not ripen properly. \n\n• Breaker stage - Dim pink colour observed on ¼ part of the fruit. Fruits are harvested at this stage to ensure the best quality. Such fruit are less prone to damage during shipment often fetch a higher price than less mature tomatoes. \n\n• Pink stage - Pink colour observed on ¾% part of the fruit. \n• Reddish pi</string>
    <string name="tomato_yield">The yield per hectare varies greatly according to variety and season. On an average, the yield varies from 20–25 t/ha. \n\nHybrid varieties may yield up to 50–60 t/ha</string>

    <string name="cauliflower_intro">Cauliflower \nS.N: Brassica oleracea var. botrytis \nFamily: Brassicaceae \nCauliflower (Brassica oleracea) is one of the most important vegetable crops of India. The edible part of cauliflower is known as curd, which consists of a shoot system with short internodes, branches apices and bracts. The edible portion of this vegetable is approximately 45 per cent of the vegetable as purchased. It has high quality of proteins and peculiar in stability of vitamin C after cooking. It is rich in minerals such as potassium, sodium, iron, phosphorus, calcium, magnesium etc.</string>
    <string name="cauliflower_climate">The optimum temperature for growth of young plants is around 23 degree C. \nIn temperate regions, the growth of young seedlings may be ceased, when temperatures are slightly about o degree c, \nLower temperatures ranging from 5 degree C to 28–30 degree C are needed for transition from vegetative to curding phase.</string>
    <string name="cauliflower_soil">Deep loamy soils with a pH range of 5.5 to 6.6 with higher organic matter content and good drainage are suited for cauliflower cultivation.</string>
    <string name="cauliflower_seed_treatment">250 g of hybrid cauliflower seed is required for the production of seedlings for 1 ha. Treat the seeds in hot water @ 500C for 30 minutes. 25g of Azospirillum is required for the seed treatment of 250g cauliflower seeds.</string>
    <string name="cauliflower_seed_rate">• Early varieties: 600–750g \n• Mid-Early season varieties: 500g \n• Mid-late varieties: 400 g \n• Late varieties: 300g</string>
    <string name="cauliflower_irrigation">First irrigation is given just after transplanting. For early and mid-season crop, usually, lesser number of irrigation is needed because of rains. In areas having rainfall, the planting is done on ridges, furrow irrigation should be given.</string>
    <string name="cauliflower_club_root">1. Club root \nControl measures: \nSeed treatment with Pseudomonas fluorescens at 10 g/kg of seeds, followed by seedling dip @ 5g/ I and soil application @ 2.5 kg/ha along with 50 kg FYM before planting. \nDip the seedlings in Carbendazim solution 2 g/l for 20 minutes. \n• Drench the soil around the seedlings in the main field with Carbendazim @ 1 g/l of water.</string>
    <string name="cauliflower_leaf_spot">2. Leaf Spot \nLeaf spot can be controlled by spraying or Carbendazim 1 g/lit</string>
    <string name="cauliflower_leaf_blight">3. Leaf Blight \nLeaf blight can be controlled by spraying Mancozeb @ 2.5 g/litre.</string>
    <string name="cauliflower_yield">Hills : 20 – 30 t/ha \nPlains 15 20 t/ha</string>

    <string name="potato_intro">Potato is the most important food crop of the world. The potato is a crop which has always been the \'poor man\'s friend\'. Potato is being cultivated in the country for the last more than 300 years. \n\nFor vegetable purposes it has become one of the most popular crops in this country. Potatoes are an economical food; they provide a source of low-cost energy to the human diet. \n\nPotatoes are a rich source of starch, vitamins especially C and B1 and minerals. They contain 20.6 per cent carbohydrates, 2.1 per cent protein, 0.3 per cent fat, 1.1 per cent crude fibre and 0.9 per cent ash.</string>
    <string name="potato_soil_and_climate">Potatoes can be produced on a wide range of soils, ranging from sandy loam, silt loam, loam and clay soil. Well drained sandy loam and medium loam sols, rich in humus are most suitable for potato. \n\nAlkaline or saline soils are not suitable for potato cultivation. They are well suited to acidic soils (pH 5.0 to 6.5) as acidic conditions tend to limit scab disease.</string>
    <string name="potato_varieties">Kufri Jyoti, Kufri Muthu, Kufri Swarna, Kufri Thangam, Kufri Malar, Kufri Soga and Kufri Giriraj are commonly cultivated.</string>
    <string name="potato_sowing1">Methods of Planting: \nThere are three methods of planting in India \n\nPlanting on ridges: \nAfter preparation of field, ridges are made at a distance of 5–60 cm with the help of spade, bullock carts or by tractors. Planting of potato is done on the ridges manually. \n\n1. Flat method: Planting of potato is done on the flat surface in shallow furrows. Ridges are made after germination when plants attain 10–12 cm height. This method is suitable for light soils. Later on two to three earthings are done to make the ridges thick. \n\nPlanting potatoes on flat surface followed by ridges: In this method field is prepared and then shallow furrows are opened on the flat surface. Potatoes are planted in furrows and immediately after planting tubers, small ridges are made. Later on these ridges are made thick by earthing up of the side soil. \n\nPlanting Time: \nTo secure high yields, it is essential to plant the potatoes at the optimum time. The best time of planting is when the maximum and minimum temperatures are from 30°C to 32°C and 18°C to 20°C, respectively. \n\nThe following time schedule should be followed for obtaining good yields. \na) Early crop-25th September to 10th October. \nb) Main crop-15th October to 25th October.</string>
    <string name="potato_sowing2">Propagation: \n• Potato is mostly cultivated by planting tubers. Purity of the cultivars and healthy seed tubers are the primary requirements for a successful crop. However, seed tuber is the costliest input in potato cultivation. \n\nThe tuber seed should be disease free, well–sprouted and 30–40 g each in weight. It is advisable to use the entire seed tuber for planting. Hill tuber seeds are split into pieces and planted late in winter when they do not decay due to mild temperatures. \n\n• Tubers should be cut longitudinally through the crown eye and the weight of the cut piece should be around 30–40 g. \n\n• Usually the seed tubers are cut with a knife just and treated with a fungicide (Captan or thiram @3g/litre of water) before planting. Before cutting the seed tuber, the knife should be disinfected with Potassium Permanganate solution. \n\nDormancy Breaking: \nCut the tubers in pieces having at least three healthy eyes and dip in 1% solution of thiourea for one hour. The planting should be done just after treatment or kept in wet gunny bags for one night. \n\nSeed Rate: \nThe seed requirements for an acre on the basis of seed size are given below: Large size– 10–12 q/acre. \nMedium size– 7–10 q/acre Small size– 4–6 q/ acre.</string>
    <string name="potato_sowing3">True Potato Seed (TPS): \n\n• To overcome the above problems True Potato Seed (TPS) is used as planting material. TPS is a botanical seed developed in the berry of the plant as a result of fertilization. \n\n• In TPS technique, the normal seed rate (2.5 t/ ha) of potato is drastically reduced to only about 200g of TPS, thereby, saving huge quantities of food material for table purposes. \n\n• Potato crop can be raised from TPS using seedling transplants or through seedling- tubers produced in preceding crop season. \n\n• In former method, the TPS seedlings raised in nursery beds are transplanted in the field and grown to maturity. While, in latter, the TPS seedlings are grown to maturity in nursery beds to obtain seedling-tubers. These seedling-tubers are used as a seed for raising normal potato crop in next season.</string>
    <string name="potato_land_preparation">The land is ploughed at a depth of 24–25 cm and exposed to the sun. \nThe soil should have a higher pore space and offer least resistance to tuber development. Well decomposed FYM (10–12 t/acre) is mixed with the soil during last ploughing.</string>
    <string name="potato_fertilizers">Organic fertilizers : \n10–20 tons of FYM. \n5 tons of Poultry manure. \n50 Kg Neem cake. \n50 Kg Pongamia cake. \n\nBio fertilizers : \n• Bio fertilizers not only played an important role in maintaining good health of the plants, but also served as a natural source of plant nutrient to increase productivity. \n\n• Some of the bio fertilizers are Pseudomonas, Trichoderma, Phosphate solubilizing bacteria (PSB) are applied at 5kg per acre along with FYM at the time of land preparation. \n\nChemical and speciality fertilizers: The requirement of Nitrogen, Phosphorus and Potassium vary with the soil type, its nutrient status, variety, cropping pattern and sources of nutrients. \n\nIt is reported that proper soil fertility management in potato, alone accounts for 20.7% of all the factors contributing yield. Generally 20–30 tonnes of FYM is recommended for potato cultivation. \n\nFoliar application : \na) Bio– Max: Dissolve 3 ml of "Bio Max and 5gms of 19:19:19 in 1 liter of water. First spray after 20days o planting and remaining sprays at 15–20 days interval. \n\nb) Total: Dissolve 5 g of "Total" in every litre of water or 1kg in 200 litres of water and spray on both surfaces of leaves. Repeat spray at monthly interval. \n\nc) Drip application: Zen Bio Fertilizer, Bumper crop kit, Bio NPK kit whenever required as per the suggestion of expert.</string>
    <string name="potato_early_blight">Symptoms : \nThe infection appears on lower leaves with necrotic spots having concentric rings. The fungus survives in the soil. In diseased plant debris. \nThe collateral host is tomato. High moisture and low temperature are favorable for disease. \n\nControl Measures : \n1. Follow crop rotation. \n2. Collect and bum plant debris after harvesting. \n3. Start sprays the crop Dithane M-45 at 0.2 per cent 30 to 35 days after planting and repeat 10 to 15 days interval if infestation is severe spray with Acrobat or curzate @ Ig/lit. \n4. Grow early blight tolerant varieties such as Kufri Naveen, Kufri Sindhuri and Kufri Jeevan.</string>
    <string name="potato_late_blight">Symptoms: \nThe infection appears at the tips or edges of the lower leaves with circular or irregular water soaked spots. White downy fungus growth appears on the underside of the leaves around the spots. \n\nCloudy weather is conducive for very fast spread of the disease. In case of sever incidence all above ground parts may show rotting. Later the disease may spread to tubers and initiate rotting. \n\nControl Measures : \n1. Plant only healthy disease free certified seed tubers. \n2. Spray the crop thoroughly with diathane M-45 (2.0 g/lit) or diathane Z- 78 (2.5 g/lit) well in advance to general appearance of disease. The spraying operations should remain continue at narrow interval of 5 to 6 days during cloudy weather with Acrobat or Equation pro @ 1g/lit Dig out tubers when foliage is completely dry or cleaned. \n3. Grow late blight resistance varieties like Kufri Navaharl. \n4. Avoid applying in excess nitrogen and irrigation.</string>
    <string name="potato_scurf">Symptom : \nThe infected plants killed, stem canker may also be formed. Affected plants may form aerial tubers. \nOn tubers, black sclerotial bodies are formed. It is a soil as well as tuber borne disease. \n\nControl Measures : \n1. Always sow certified seeds \n2. Treat the seed tubers with any organo mercurial fungicides containing 6 per cent mercury \n{agallol, aretan, emisan etc.) for about 5 to 10 minutes before the planting and also seed tubers before keeping in the cold storage. \n3. Dip the tubers in 1.75 per cent solution of sulfuric acid for 20 minutes.</string>
    <string name="potato_common_scab">Symptom : \nIt survives in soil years together and on infected tubers in cold storage. It may also spread through manure. Affected tubers show the superficial roughened areas of corky tissue, often slightly below the plane of healthy skin of tubers. Low soil moisture is favourable for proliferation of causal pathogen. \nControl Measures : \n1. Obtain healthy, disease free seed tubers for planting. \n2. Disinfect the tubers by dipping in suspension of mercurial fungicide e.g. emisan-6 or agallol- 6 at 0.25 per cent concentration for 5 minutes. \n3. Plant the tubers shallow and Keep the soil wet during tuberization. \n4. Follow crop rotation with non-host crops including beets, carrot etc. \n5. Maintain soil pH 5.0 to 5.3.</string>
    <string name="potato_charcoal_rot">Symptom : \nThe roots of the affected plants become brown in colour. The rotting starts on the stem portion. The skin of the stern becomes ash coloured. Line dark lesions appear at the lenticels of the tubers and also round the stern end of tuber. \nCharcoal rot is common during the hot and dry months in late season crops. \n\nControl Measures : \n1. Obtain disease free seed tubers for planting. Hill potatoes are nearly free from this pathogen. Alankar or Kufri Chandramukhi. \n2. Grow early maturing varieties such as Kufri \n3. Irrigate crop at regular intervals. \n4. Seed tubers may be treated with agalal-6 or aretan at 0.25 per cent solution before storage. The treated tubers should not be eaten.</string>
    <string name="potato_harvesting_and_yield">The time of harvest is very important in potato. The development of tuber continues till vines die. The main crop is ready for harvest within 75–120 days of planting depending upon the area, soil type abd variety sown. \n\nYellowing of the potato plants leaves and easy separation of the tubers from their stolons indicate that the crop has reached maturity. \n\nYield \n6–8 tons/acre of tuber yield</string>

    <string name="brinjal_intro">Brinjal (Solanum melongena L) is an important vegetable crop of subtropics and tropics in India. Its fruits are good source of calcium, phosphorus, iron and vitamins particularly vitamin \'B\'. Brinjal is grown in an area of 0.72 million ha with production of 13.44 million tones and 18.70 tones/ ha productivity. \n\nThe crop is grown extensively in warm climates mainly in India, Bangladesh, Pakistan, China and Philippines. It requires long growing season with high average day and night temperature. \n\nThere are several names by which the crop is known in India, but brinjal is the most familiar. Brinjal is also called \'eggplant\' or \'aubergine\'. It is a perennial but grown commercially as an annual crop. \n\nA number of cultivars are grown in India, consumer preference being dependent upon fruit colour, size and shape.</string>
    <string name="brinjal_climate">Brinjal can be grown in almost all types of soils. But well drained clay loam is ideal for its cultivation. \n\nWilt sick soils are not suitable. Well drained soil rich in organic matter with pH of 6.5–7.5.Though it is a warm season crop, but can be grown in all the three seasons of the year. \n\nJune-July, October-November and January-February. A daily mean temperature of 15 to 210C is most favourable for optimum growth and yield. \n\nSeason of planting : December - January &amp; May - June.</string>
    <string name="brinjal_land_selection_and_preparation">The soil should be thoroughly prepared by ploughing 4 to 5 times before transplanting theseedlings. \nBulky organic manures like well rotten crowding or compost should be incorporated evenly on the soil.</string>
    <string name="brinjal_varieties">Long Vareities : \n\nPusa purple Long: Early variety, ready for picking in about 75–80 days after sowing during autumn–winter season and takes 100–110 days during spring–summer season. After normal transplanting it becomes ready for picking in about 45 days. \n\nCommonly grown in Punjab, Delhi and Western Uttar Pradesh. It has semi–erect to bushy habit, medium in height. Fruits are long, slender, purple, and glossy. It is heavy yielder. Average yield is 300 q/ha. \n\nPusa Purple Cluster : \nA medium– early variety. Fruits are 10–12 cm long, deep purple in colour and borne in clusters of 4–9 suitable for southern and northern hills, moderately resistant to bacteria wilt. \n\nArka Keshev : \nFruits 18–20 cm long. 5–6 cm in diameter and dark purple. They are bright, soft and contain less seed. Yields 300–400 q/ha. \n\nRound Varieties : \nPusa Purple Round:.\ It is tolerant to little leaf and shoots and fruit borer. Average yield is 350–400q/ha \n\nPant Rituraj : \nFruits are almost round. Attractive purple in colour, soft, less seeded and endowed with good flavour. Average yield is 400q/ha. It possesses field resistance to bacterial wilt. \n\nArka Kusumaker : \nFruits small, long, borne in clusters of 5 to 7, good in texture and cooking qualities and skin light green. Average yield is 330 q/ha. \n\nOval Varieties : \nArka Navneet (F1): Fruits oval– round and free from bitterness. Fruit skin attractive, deep purple, Flesh soft and while with few seeds. Yield is 650– 700 q/ha.</string>
    <string name="brinjal_seed_treatment">• Treat the seeds with Trichoderma viride @ 4 g/kg or Pseudomonas fluorescens @ 10 g/kg of seed. \n• Treat the seeds with Azospirillum @ 40 g / 400 g of seeds using rice gruel as adhesive. \n• In raised nursery beds, sow the seeds in lines at 10 cm apart and cover with sand. \n• Transplant the seedlings 30–35 days after sowing at 60 cm apart in the ridges.</string>
    <string name="brinjal_seed_rate">Varieties: 400 g/ha \nHybrids: 200 g/ha.</string>
    <string name="brinjal_water_management">In plains irrigation should be applied every third to fourth day during hot weather and every 7 to 12 days during winter. \nIrrigation is given before top dressing if there is no rain. The brinjal field should be regularly irrigated to keep the soil moist during frosty days.</string>
    <string name="brinjal_bacterial_wilt">1. Bacterial Wilt: (Pseudomonas solanacearum) \n\nSymptoms: \nThe characteristic symptoms include wilting of the foliage followed by collapse of the entire plant. \nThe wilting is characterized by dropping and slight yellowing of leaves and vascular discolouration. \nDrying of plants at the time of flowering and fruiting are also characteristic to the disease condition. \nThe infected cut stems pieces when dipped in water, a white milky stream of bacterial oozes coming out which is the diagnostic symptom for bacterial wilt. \n\nManagement : \nRogue out the infected plants and destroy them Seed treatment with Streptocycline (150 ppm) for 90 minutes. \nSpray 0.5 g. Streptomycine - sulphate with 3.0g. Copper oxychloride in a lit. water. Repeat the spray at 20 days intervals. \nCrop rotation with cruciferous vegetables such as cauliflower or ragi or maize or Jowar once in two yearshelp in reducing the disease incidence. Spray Copper fungicides to control the disease (2% Bordeaux mixture).</string>
    <string name="brinjal_cercospora_leaf_spot">2. Cercospora Leaf Spot: Cercospora solani -melongenae. \n\nSymptoms : \n• The spots are brown and irregular in shape. Concentric rings are present in them. Several spots may coalesce to form larger necrotic patches \n• Fruits are also affected. Large, necrotic sunken spots develop on the fruit which turns yellow and drops. \n• Diseased crop debris in soil is the main source of primary inoculum. \n\nManagement : \n• Spraying 1 per cent Bordeaux mixture or 2 g Copper oxychloride 50 WP per liter of water effectively controls leaf spots. \n• Seed treatment with Carbendazim 50 WP @ 2g per kg followed by Trichoderma viridae @ 4 g per kg of seed 24 hours prior to sowing gives adequate control. \n• Spraying Mancozeb 75 % WP @ 3 g per liter of water to the point of run-off effectively controls the disease.</string>
    <string name="brinjal_alternaria_leaf_spot">3. Alternaria leaf Spot: Alternaria melongenae \n\nSymptoms : \n• The spots are brown and irregular in shape. Concentric rings are present in them. Several spots may coalesce to form larger necrotic patches. \n• Fruits are also affected. Large, necrotic sunken spots develop on the fruit which turns yellow and drops. \n\nManagement : \nSpray 2.0g. Mancozeb 75 WP OR 2.0g. Chlorothaolonil 70 WP. in a lit. water.</string>
    <string name="brinjal_damping_off">4. Damping Off \n\nPre-emergence damping-off: The pre-emergence damping off results in seed and seedling rot before these emerge out of the soil. Post-emergence damping-off: \n\nThe post-emergence damping off phase is characterized by infection of the young, juvenile tissues of the collar at the ground level. The infected tissues become soft and become water soaked. The collar portion rots and ultimately the seedlings collapse and die.. \n\nManagement : \n• The seed should be treated with Thiram @ 2g/ kg of seed before sowing. \n• Drench the base of the seedlings with 3.0 g. Metalaxyl- MZ 72 WP or 0.1 per cent copper oxy chloride (10g/liter). \n• application of bio-control agent Trichoderma viride in soil @ 1kg/acre is also found effective to control damping-off to considerable extent. \n• Seed treatment with Carbendazim @ 2 g per kg followed by Trichoderma viride @ 4 g per kg of seed 24 hours prior to sowing gives adequate control.</string>
    <string name="brinjal_harvesting">• The first harvest starts from 55–60 days after transplanting. \n• High yields will be produced if fruits are harvested before they reach full size, provided they are well colored and of good size. \n• Fruits are harvested by hand at immature and mature sizes, while the skin is still glossy, but before the skin toughens and seeds become matured. \n• The harvesting should be done early in the morning or in the late evening to protect the fruits from the heat of the day. \n• Harvest can be made once in 5 days and as many as 15 to 20 pickings are made.</string>
    <string name="brinjal_yield">• Varieties: 25 to 30 t/ha \n• Hybrids: 60 – 80 t/ha</string>

    <string name="cabbage_intro">Cabbage (Brassica oleracea var capitata) is a typical cool season crop grown for the thickened main bud called head. It is a rich source of vitamin A, C and mineral including potassium, calcium, sodium and iron. Plants flower generally after winter. It is good sources of protein (1.3 per cent) which contains all essential amino acids, particularly sulphur containing amino acids. Flavour in cabbage leaves is due to the glycoside sinigrin. Cabbage contains goitrogens which cause enlargement of thyroid glands. Cabbage is commonly used as cooked vegetable. It also makes into a good salad mixed in tomato, green chillies, beet root, etc. The major cabbage producing states are Uttar Pradesh, Odisha, Bihar, Assam, West Bengal, Maharashtra and Karnataka.</string>
    <string name="cabbage_climate">It is essentially a winter vegetable and prefers cool climate. It can be grown both during monsoon (June - July) and winter (October-November). Late transplanting in winter will result in poor formation of the head. The optimum soil temperature for seed germination is 12 to 16 degree C.</string>
    <string name="cabbage_soil">Well drained medium black to red loamy soil are ideal for its cultivation. The crop cannot be grown in water logged and highly acidic soil. A pH range of 6.0–6.5 is considered as optimum for growing cabbage. Plants growing in saline soils are prone to diseases.</string>
    <string name="cabbage_season_of_sowing">June - July or October - November is suitable season.</string>
    <string name="cabbage_seed_treatment">Treat the seeds in hot water @ 50°C for 30 minutes. 40g of Azospirillum is required for the seed treatment of 400g cabbage seeds.</string>
    <string name="cabbage_seed_rate">350–400 gm/acre of seeds is required.</string>
    <string name="cabbage_land_preparation">For preparation of field, soil is ploughed 2–3 times with power tiller or with spade. Planking is done during the last ploughing to make friable soil bed for transplanting. Raised beds of 1 m width, 4–5 m length and 30 cm above the soil are prepared.</string>
    <string name="cabbage_damping_off">1. Damping Off: (Pythium aphinidermatum) \nSymptoms : \nDamping off of Cabbage occurs in two stages, i.e. the pre–emergence and the post– emergence phase. \nIn the pre–emergence the phase the seedlings are killed just before they reach the soil surface. The young radical and the plumule are killed and there is complete rotting of the seedlings. \nThe post–emergence phase is characterized by the infection of the young, juvenile tissues of the collar at the ground level. \n\nManagement : \n• Seed treatment with Thiram or Captan @ 2.5–3 g/kg of seed. \n• The seedlings should be treated with Hexaconazole 5% + Captan 70% WP or Metalaxyl-M + 640 g/kg Mancozeb @ 2g/l of water.</string>
    <string name="cabbage_black_rot">2. Black rot: Xanthomonas campestris pv. campestris \nSymptoms : \nFirst appear as chlorotic or yellow (angular) areas near the leaf margins \nYellow area extends to veins and midrib forming characteristic \'v\' shaped chlorotic spots which later turn black \nVeins and veinlets turn brown and finally black Vascular blackening extend beyond affected veins to midrib, petiole and stem \nIn advanced stages, infection may reach the roots system and blackening of vascular bundles occurs. Bacterial ooze can also be seen on affected parts \nIf the infection is early, the plants wilt and die. \n\nManagement : \nAvoid planting in fields infested with weeds in the crucifer family, which may harbor the black rot organism from previous years. \nCrop rotation for every once in two years. \nSeed treatment with 0.5 g. Streptocyclene + 3.0 g. Copper oxychloride in a lit. water. \nSpray 0.5 g. Streptocyclene or 0.5 g. K- cyclone or 100 mg. Tetracyclene hydroxide or 0.5 g.Streptomycin sulphate with 3.0 g. Copperoxychloride 50 WP/liter water.</string>
    <string name="cabbage_downey_mildew">3. Downy Mildew (Peronospora parasitica) \nSymptoms : \nSmall purplish brown spots on under surface of leaves \nSmall, pale yellow angular spots on upper surface of leaves, with downy growth on theunder surface. The spots coalesce and the leaves shrivel and dries up prematurely \nIn cabbage, these spots expose the heads to soft rot. \nStems show dark brown and depressed lesions or streaks which later develop downy growth of fungus. \n\nManagement : \nRemoval of crop debris and weed hosts may reduce inoculum. \nPractice rotation with non-brassica crops. Spray 2.0 g. Metalaxyl- MZ 72 WP or 2.0 g. Cymoxanil + Mancozeb/lit.water. Chlorothalonil 75 WP @2gm/liter and Difenoconazole 250 EC @ 2ml/liter per acre.</string>
    <string name="cabbage_white_rust">4. White rust (Albugo candida) \nSymptoms : \n• White, shiny raised blisters (pustules) on the lower surfaces of leaves, stems and flowers \n• Pustules coalesce to form irregular patches \n• The epidermis ruptures exposing white spore mass which gives the pustule a powdery appearance \n• Distortion of the floral parts including petals, pistils and anthers due to hypertrophy and Hyperplasia. \n\nManagement : \nSpray 2.0 g. Mancozeb 75WP or 2.0 g. Zineb 75 WP or 2.0 g. Metalaxyl- MZ 72 WP or 2.0 g Cymoxanil + Mancozeb/liter water.</string>
    <string name="cabbage_harvesting">Cabbage is ready for harvest at 90–120 days after planting. Cabbage should be harvested when the heads are firm and mature. Delaying harvest, beyond maturity can result in split heads and increased incidence of field disease. \nThe head is harvested by bending it to one side and cutting it with a knife. The stalk should be cut flat and as close to the head as possible, yet long enough to retain two to four wrapper leaves. Extra leaves act as cushions during handling and may be desired in certain markets.</string>
    <string name="cabbage_yield">Average yield obtained from early varieties is 12–14 t/acre and that of late type is 18–20 t/acre.</string>

    <string name="chilli_intro">It is known as the most valuable crop of India. It is used as a principle ingredient of various curries and chutneys, also used in vegetables, spices, condiments, sauces and pickles. Pungency in chillies is due to the active constituent "Capsaicin", an alkaloid. The native home of chilli is considered to be Mexico with secondary origin of Guatemala. Chilli was introduced in India by the Portuguese in Goa in the middle of 17th century and since then it had rapidly spread throughout the country.</string>
    <string name="chilli_climate">The chili is a plant of tropical and sub–tropical region –It grows well in warm and humid climate and a temperature of 20–25°C. Low moisture in soil during blossom development and fruit formation causes the bud, deblossom and fruit drops.</string>
    <string name="chilli_soil">Chilli is grown in many types of soils–sandy to heavy clay. A well–drained, fairly light fertile loam with a fair moisture holding capacity is ideal. The light soils produce better quality fruits than heavy soils. Chilli crop prefers a soil reaction ranging from pH 6–7.</string>
    <string name="chilli_sowing_and_seed">Time of sowing : \nThe ideal time for raising nursery is from October end to mid of November. Cover the nursery area with 50% shade net and cover the sides using 40/50 mesh insect proof nylon net. Seedlings are ready for transplantation in 30–40 days (Usually in February – March). \n\nSpacing : \nUse row to row spacing of 75 cm and plant to plant spacing of 45 cm. \n\nMethod of sowing : \nTransplantation method is used. \n\nSeed Rate : \nFor varieties use seed rate of 200 gm/acre and 80–100 gm/acre for hybrids. \nNursery area: 100 sq.m / ha. \n\nSeed Treatment : \nTo protect crop from various soil borne disease seed treatment is necessary. Before sowing do seed treatment with Thiram@3gm or Carbendazim @2gm/kg. \nAfter chemical treatment, treat seed with Trichoderma@5gm/kg or Pseudomonas fluorescens@10gm/kg. Keep it in shade and use it for sowing. Do watering with rosecan on daily basis. \nDrench the nursery with Copper oxychloride @ 2.5gm/ltr of water at 15 days interval to prevent crop from damping off disease. \nTo protect against wilt, sucking pest, dip roots for 15 min in Trichoderma harzianum @ 20gm/ Ltr +0.5 ml/Ltr Imidacloprid before transplanting. Seedling inoculation with VAM supplemented with nitrogen fixing bacteria, save super phosphate by 50% along with saving of 25% nitrogen application. \n\nFor seed treatment use any one fungicide from the following : \nCarbendazim 2 gm/kg seeds. \nThiram 3 gm/kg seeds. \n\nSpacing \nVarieties 60 x 45 cm \nHybrids 75 x 60 cm</string>
    <string name="chilli_land_preparation">Thoroughly prepare the field with the addition of FYM @ 25 t/ha and form ridges and furrows at a spacing of 60 cm. Apply 2 kg/ha of Azospirillum and 2 kg/ha of Phosphobacteria by mixing with 20 kg of FYM. Irrigate the furrows and transplant 40–45 days old seedlings, with the ball of earth on the ridges.</string>
    <string name="chilli_damping_off">1. Damping off: Pythium aphanidermatum \n• The populations in nursery seedlings die due to this diseases. \n• Mycelium are hyaline and Aseptate and its has width size 5 micron. \n• Irregular mycelial fibers grown and thus produce irregular shape spores. \n\nSymptoms : \n• Seedlings killed before emergence. \n• Water soaking and shrivelling of stem. \n• Factors favouring infection: Moist soils poordrainage 90–100% R.H soil temperature 20°C. \n• Impact of disease symptoms shown at after sowing of seeds in seed beds. \n• It will reduce the seed germination percentage. \n• It affects the young seedlings and their stems. \n\nManagement : \n• Soil drenching with Copper oxychloride 0.25%. \n• avoid shade places for nursery establishment. \n• use recommended seed rate. \n• avoid flooding type of irrigation and maintain optimum moisture level in nursery. \n• use Thiram or Capton @ 4g/ kg of seeds for seed rate</string>
    <string name="chilli_powdery_mildew">2.Powdery mildew: Leveillula taurica \nSymptoms : \n• Shedding of foliage. \n• white powdery growth on lower side of leaves. \n\nManagement : \nSpray Wettable sulphur 0.25% or Dinocap (Karathane) 0.05%.</string>
    <string name="chilli_cercospora_leaf_spot">3. Cercospora leaf spot :Cercospora capsici \nSymptoms : \n• Leaf lesions typically are brown and circular with small to large light grey centres and dark brown margins. The lesions may enlarge to Icm or more in diameter and some times coalesce. \n• Stem, petiole and pod lesions also have light grey centres with dark borders, but they are typically elliptical. \n• Severely infected leaves drop off prematurely resulting in reduced yield. \n\nManagement : \n• Spray twice at 10–15 days interval with Mancozeb 0.25% or Chlorothalonil (Kavach) 0.1%.</string>
    <string name="chilli_harvest">Harvesting can be done 75 days after transplanting. First two picking yield green chilli and subsequently yield red ripe fruits.</string>
    <string name="chilli_yield">Yield \nVarieties: 2–3 t/ha of dry pods or 10 – 15 t/ha of Hybrids : 25 t/ha of green chillies. \nHybrids : 25 t/ ha of green chillies.</string>

    <string name="onion_intro">Onion is most widely cultivated popular vegetable species. It is used for culinary purpose also it has several non-culinary use like it is used as Moth repellent because of its pungent juice, \n\nIt is used to polish glass and copperware, onion concentrated water can be spray on plants to increased plants pest resistance. India ranks first in term of area and second in production after China.</string>
    <string name="onion_climate">Onion is a temperate crop but can be grown under a wide range of climatic conditions such as temperate, tropical and subtropical climate. The best performance can be obtained in a mild weather without the extremes of cold and heat and excessive rainfall. However, onion plant is hardy and in the young stage can withstand freezing temperature also. In India, short–day onion is grown in the plains and requires 10–12 hours day length. \n\nThe long–day onion is grown in hills requiring 13–14 hours day length. For vegetative growth, lower temperature combined with short photoperiod is required whereas relatively higher temperature along with longer photoperiod is required for bulb development and maturity. \n\nThe optimum temperature for vegetative phase and bulb development is 13–24C and 16–25C, respectively. It requires about 70% relative humidity for good growth. It can grow well in places where the average annual rainfall is 650–750 mm with good distribution during the monsoon period. Areas with low (̌650 mm) or heavy rainfall (>750 mm) are not particularly suitable for rain-fed crop.</string>
    <string name="onion_soil">It can be cultivated on various soil types such as sandy loam, clay loam silt loam and heavy soils. It gives best result when grown in deep loam and alluvial soils with good drainage, moisture holding capacity and sufficient organic matter. \n\nLoose and sandy soils are not suitable for cultivation as bulb produce in such soil are deformed with less keeping quality. pH of soil should be 6 to 7.</string>
    <string name="onion_sowing_and_seed">Time of sowing \nOptimum time for raising nursery is middle of October to middle of November month. Seedlings are ready for transplantation in middle of December to Middle of January month. For transplanting, select 10–15 cm heighted healthy seedlings. \n\nSpacing \nTo get higher yield, while transplanting, use spacing of 15 cm between rows and 7.5 cm between plants. \n\nSowing Depth \nIn nursery, sow seeds at depth of 1–2 cm.</string>
    <string name="onion_method_of_sowing">Method of sowing \nFor sowing use transplanting method. \n\nSeed Rate \nSeed rate of 4–5 kg is sufficient for raising seedling required for one acre land. \n\nSeed Treatment \nSeed treatment with Thiram@2 gm/kg of seed + Benomyl 50WP@1 gm/liter water effectively controls damping off and smut diseases. After chemical treatment, seed treatment with bio agent Trichoderma viride@2 gm/kg of seed is recommended, it help in reducing early seedling diseases and soil borne inoculum.</string>
    <string name="onion_land_preparation">Give three to four deep ploughing and bring soil to fine tilth. Add well decomposed cow dung to increase organic content of soil. Then levelled the soil and divide into small plots and channels.</string>
    <string name="onion_fertilizers">Apply 20 tonnes of Farm Yard Manure or well decomposed cow dung 10 days before sowing. Apply Nitrogen@40 kg, Phophorus@20 kg and Potash@20 kg in form of Urea@90 kg, \n\nSingle Super Phosphate@125 kg per acre and MOP@35 kg/acre. Apply whole quantity of Phosphorus, Potash and half dose of Nitrogen at time of transplanting. Apply remaining amount of nitrogen as top dressing, four weeks after transplantation. \n\n10–15 days after transplanting, spray 19:19:19 along with CRIYAGEN BIOHUMATE@3ml/Ltr of water. \n\nIn addition to NPK, sulphur is also an essential plant nutrient important for onion crop for improving yield and the pungency of onion bulbs. Soil application of 15–20 kg S/ha is recommended for long day onion crops. \n\nSulphur is recommended as basal dose at the time of transplanting.</string>
    <string name="onion_purple_blotch">In severe infestation may cause yield loss up to 70%. Deep purple lesions are observed on leaves. Yellow streaks get turn brown and extend along the blade. \n\nManagement \nTake spray of Propineb 70%WP@350 gm/acre/ 150 ltr of water, twice at 10 days interval Spray Blitox 50 300g/acre or azoxystrobin 300g/ acre</string>
    <string name="onion_basal_rot">Management \nSeed or bulb treatment with Trichoderma viride, @ 4g/kg and basal application of T. viride,@2.5kg/ha along with VAM 12.5 kg/ha.</string>
    <string name="onion_harvesting">Harvesting at proper time is necessary. It depend upon variety, season, market price etc. 50% neck falls is sign indicating crop is ready for harvesting. \n\nHarvesting is done manually by uprooting bulbs. After harvesting they are kept in field for 2–3 days to remove excessive moisture from bulb.</string>
    <string name="onion_yield">During hot days when soil is hard, bulbs are pulled out with a hand–hoe.12–16 t/ha in 70 to 90 days.</string>

    <string name="coriander_intro">Coriander is an annual herb and belongs to the family of Apiaceae and coriander is indispensable spice in the kitchen. \n\nIt gives good flavor to dish, because of this property coriander seed (Dhaniya) and fresh leaves are common used in every kitchen to prepare testy dishes. \n\nThe fresh leaves are an ingredient in many Indian foods (such as curries, chutneys and salads). Coriander leaves constitute one of the richest source of Vitamin \'C\'. \n\nAll parts of the coriander plant are eatable, but the fresh coriander leaves and the dried seeds (Dhaniya) are the parts most traditionally used in cooking. coriander leaves also called as Coriandrum sativums, Chinese parsley, Cilantro, Dhania patta.</string>
    <string name="coriander_climate">Coriander grows well in dry and cool weather. It does not tolerate any frost. Coriander performs well at a temperature range of 20 to 30 °C.</string>
    <string name="coriander_soil">Coriander grows well in well drained loamy soils. The Optimum PH range 6 to 8 in soil is best suited for its cultivation.</string>
    <string name="coriander_sowing_and_seeding">1. Time of sowing \nJune to July &amp; October to November n\n2. Method of sowing \nThe seeds are directly sown in lines or broadcasted in the main field or transplanting. \n\n3. Seed rate and plant geometry \n5–6 kg/acre (Irrigated crop) and 10 – 12 kg/ acre (Rainfed crop) \nWhole seed will not germinate and hence the seeds are split open into halves before sowing for more germination percentage \n\n4. Seed Treatment \nSeeds are to be treated with Azospirillum @ 3 packets/ha. Seed treatment with Trichoderma viride @4 g/kg of seed has to be done to control wilt disease. \n\nPre sowing seed hardening treatment with Potassium Dihydrogen Phosphate @ 10 grams/ liter water for 16 hours should be done for rainfed crop condition.</string>
    <string name="coriander_land_preparation">Prepare the main field to a fine tilth and form beds and channels (for irrigated crop). Basal FYM 5 t/acre</string>
    <string name="coriander_fertilizers">5 kg N, 20 kg P and 10 kg K for rainfed and irrigated crops. Top dressing Top dressing may be done at 5 kg N/acre 30 days after sowing for the irrigated crop only Apply Criyagen DNP 2 bags as basal dose/acre. \n\nUse Criyagen Zyme: 3ml/liter + 19:19:19 3g/liter for plant development</string>
    <string name="coriander_powdery_mildew">Symptoms : \nIt appears as small, white, powdery patches on young parts of stems, leaves and buds which increases in size, and coalesce to cover entire area of leaf surface. \n\nAffected leaves are reduced in size and distorted. Premature sterility is also common. in serve cases, the umbels dry up. \nSeed formation may not take place in affected plants due to this disease. \n\nManagement : \nSpray with wettable sulphur 0.2 percent.</string>
    <string name="coriander_wilt">Symptoms : \nThe disease can easily be recognized in the field by drooping of the terminal portions, followed by withering and drying up of leaves, eventually resulting in death. \n\nDiscoloration of vascular system of the root is observed. Partial wilting is also found. In partially wilted plants, growth is arrested. \n\nThe leaves become pinkish yellow to yellow. Sterility is often noticed in such plants. Seeds, if formed are immature and light in weight. Severe infection in the early stage results in total failure of the crop. \n\nManagement : \nSeed treatment with Carbendazim @ 2g/kg of seeds. \nSeed treatment with Pseudomonas fluorescens @10g/kg of seeds. \nSoil drenching with Carbendazim 0.1% or copper oxy chloride 0.25%.</string>
    <string name="coriander_stem_gall">Symptoms : \nThe disease appears in the form of tumor-like swellings of leafStem gallveins, leaf stalks, peduncles, stems as well as fruits. The infected veins show a swollen hanging appearance to the leaves. \n\nInitially the tumors are glossy which rupture later on and become rough. They are about 3 mm broad and up to 12.5 mm long. \n\nBadly affected plants may be killed. In the presence of excessive soil moisture, especially under shaded conditions, when the stem fails to harden and remain succulent, the tumors are numerous. \n\nManagement : \nTo control the disease, sowing may be done only by treating the seeds with 4 g Thiram and 2 g Bavistin / Kg. seeds. \n\nSpray 0.1% solution of Carbendazim when the symptoms start appearing and repeat the spraying at an interval of 20 days till the disease is completely controlled.</string>
    <string name="coriander_harvesting">The plants are pulled just when the fruits are fully ripe but green and start drying. The plants are dried and thrashed with sticks, winnowed and cleaned. For leaf, pull out the plants when they are 30–40 days old.</string>
    <string name="coriander_yield">Rainfed Grain yield: 150–200 kg/acre Irrigated 250–300 kg/ acre Leaf yield: 3–3.5 t/ acre</string>

</resources>